LAUGHING MAN FANSUBS
Angels and demons were circling over me,
Crossing a brambly path of stars and milky ways.
He who does not perceive his calling,
does not know true happiness.
Watch in awe! Watch in awe!
Flying in glory, Flying in glory
I am calling, calling now. Spirits rise and falling.
To be with you longer
Calling, calling...
in the depth of longing
To stay myself longer
The flow may swallow you, flying in glory
What's this?
Internal documents from a social welfare
facility owned by the Ministry of Justice.
A social welfare facility?
A place where they temporarily isolate those
with serious cyberbrain closed shell syndrome,
and train them so they can re-enter society.
You've heard about it before, right?
Last week, the Ministry of Health,
Labour, and Welfare's database
suffered a large-scale hack that
originated from that facility.
The stolen information included
top-secret material rated Class A or higher.
Look at how quickly they got past the protection.
Whoever did this got through three different layers of
offensive protection in less than two hours.
If one person did this,
that person is better than the Major.
Better than the Major?
I had Ishikawa and Bouma do a careful trace,
so I'm pretty sure that the
hacking took place from there.
But the weird thing is that the
facility's line is usually turned off,
so it's impossible for data from the
inside to go outside and vice versa.
In addition to that,
the Ministry's reaction was strange as well.
They had top-secret data stolen,
yet they have no filed any damage reports.
Although it was a disgrace for them to get
hacked, it's unusual to not report it.
There must be something they want to keep secret,
and there's a risk we'd tip them off
if we just barge in.
So...
An inside investigation, eh?
Inside
The Forest
of the
Sub-Imagos
Note: An imago is an insect
in its pre adult stage
The communication room...
It's just as the report said,
this area doesn't even have power.
What's wrong?
Connect...
I'm going to connect today.
Hey.
Who are you?
We found him.
You must be the new trainee.
I'm the chief, Marta.
I'm Togusa.
Bad boy, you're supposed to be
working with everyone else right now.
Connect...
Today's the day I connect.
Do you have your cyberbrain in closed-mode?
Yes.
Get out of the way!
Warn him.
Today's the day I connect.
Yes, you're right.
But it's time to work right now.
I'll go to Virtual City Alpha.
Today's... Today's the day I connect.
Today's the day I connect.
Hey!
Catch him.
Hurry!
Don't let your guard down.
Thank you. That helped.
Don't worry, he's just sleeping.
Is that so.
What was that?
We have a rule here that a staff member must be
present when connecting to the outside world.
And this place has been unusable
since yesterday, so he panicked.
Please sit.
Thank you.
He obsesses over schedules and sequence.
Still, the way you handled it was quite rough.
The public has a strong belief that a person with
cyberbrain closed shell syndrome can't deal with the net.
But the problem is that they have
too strong of an affinity for it.
Too strong of an affinity?
Yes.
Once they desire to connect with the Internet
or someone, they try to do it no matter what.
If it's with a certain person, they try to share
their thoughts thus committing a ghost hack,
or they even get fried by the other person's
offensive protection and die.
But, there are some cases where they close themselves off
inside their protection and refuse to communicate with others,
and thus are not able to come back.
This is the sector where children with serious
symptoms like those gather together around noon.
To prevent the accidents that you mentioned,
you need to isolate them from the network.
Because it protects them as well.
That's your reasoning, correct?
But, do they really possess the ability to deploy a
substitute protection like the boy I just met?
You will understand after seeing this.
This is a danger zone in a way.
Cyberbrain closed shell syndrome and mental
handicap may happen at the same time...
But they show incredible aptitude
in the cyber world most of the time.
I have them program protection mazes as training
for jobs that make use of their syndrome's traits.
Sometimes, someone makes a very good protection;
some of those are adopted
by government organisations,
They are all very unique.
If I leave them like this, they will assemble
and disassemble protection codes all day long.
I think I've shown you everything now.
Yes...
I will leave you in charge of one community room.
His name is Aoi, you will be in charge of him.
Yes, ma'am.
I think the other children have already
returned, please take care of them.
I understand.
Aoi, right? Nice to meet you.
You're late, Aoi. Where were...?
Hi.
I'm going to be in charge here
starting today, I'm Togusa.
Nice to meet you.
Want to play catch?
It's still bright outside.
Hey, give that back!
He wants it back.
Oh...
He panics when his glove is lost.
And no one here wants to go outside.
Are you guys treated badly?
Hey! The leader said that he'd come back again!
Really?!
Yeah, a message just came in.
I'm surprised; he came here just a week ago.
A week ago?
Who's this leader you're talking about?
You're sharp, Mister.
What?
We don't know if we can trust you or not.
Yeah.
So, we can't talk to you so carelessly.
You're strict.
Of course.
I'll go let the others know.
Okay.
He's late.
Are you worried about him?
No way.
He's slow, so I was wondering
if he screwed up or something.
Who are you calling slow?
You're late! What were you doing?
Well, um... It took time for me to setup
a connection without being caught...
Since this is the only place that
has a line connected to the outside.
So?
This facility uses people with cyberbrain closed shell
syndrome to program and disassemble protection mazes.
If there's someone in here who
can make use of that technology...
That would explain the skillful hacking done to
the Ministry of Health, Labour and Welfare.
I see. So, are there any clues as to who did it?
No, not yet.
But there are heavily armoured cyborgs here.
It's a weird facility.
Understood, resume covert investigation.
Roger.
Oh, Major, there's one more
thing that caught my attention.
What?
Who do you think "leader" refers to?
Leader as in, a leader?
Yes, the children at the
facility were using that word.
and said he came to the facility last week.
I see. We'll try running a phonetic search on our end, but...
You try to gather information about that
person before your next periodic report.
Roger.
That means someone else other
than me is using this place.
I thought what I'd do was, I'd pretend I
was one of those deaf-mutes or should I?
What's this?
Oil paint?
Wow, that's good.
It looks like a photograph,
but you're not going to paint it on that canvas?
Do you know who this "leader" is?
He's going to create a beautiful world.
He's going to look at a new heart.
Good morning.
What?
I'm not going to tell you about the leader.
I know.
Have you seen something like that before?
It's extremely cool, isn't it?
You guys can read quasi-image programs?
What, you can't?
Yeah...
Then try connecting with his brain.
You'll see something interesting.
But be careful.
Last time a staff member
tried to dive into his brain,
their consciousness got mixed
up and now he's a goner.
So, what are you going to do?
No, I'll pass.
How boring.
You're more of a coward than I thought.
Hey, who's this leader you all talk about?
Please take care of the rest.
Oh, it's you.
I appreciate your hard work.
Are you going somewhere?
Yes, to a conference on welfare businesses.
Is that so? Have a safe trip.
Sorry...
Hold on a minute, I'll be done in no time.
There are oil paintings here as well.
There are no suspicious documents here.
And no one visited here last week.
Damn it...
It's so inconvenient when I
can't access outside documents.
We can't have this.
Are you spying on us while leaving
the one you're in charge of alone?
You won't find information on the
leader even if you search there.
Looks like I'm in no position to make excuses.
Hurt him, but don't kill him.
Hold on a sec.
If we fight here, this precious picture will...
Are you trying to fight me with that?
I was trying to warn you not
to let the picture go to waste.
Unlike electronic information, it can't be copied.
You thought I was unarmed?
Public Safety Section 9?
Major, all the terminals in the
facility went online just now.
Did something happen?
They're trying to crack our access code.
Did they find out?
I don't know.
Shut off all the lines.
What are you doing?!
They're locked!
Batou, we're going to get Togusa out of there!
Ishikawa, get control of all
the lines in the facility.
Saitou, clear a path for our retreat!
Yes! I burned the AI of the
guy who was spying on us!
Kuroha.
Leader! Where were you?
Something bad happened,
someone from the outside found out.
A lot of adults will be coming here soon.
I have to get out of here before that happens.
Why?
You were able to get through
these situations before.
We'll protect you this time, too.
No, I had to leave here soon anyway.
Wait! Are you going to erase
Onba's and my memories as well?
I did it!
Unfortunately...
I see...
So, I can't cheer you on from
Virtual City Alpha anymore.
Okay, but we don't want to forget about you.
Can you leave something behind?
Okay, I promise.
Togusa!
Hey, Togusa!
Togusa, what happened? Togusa!
Hey, wake up, Togusa.
Togusa!
So, is there any proof that the boy
Togusa was speaking of, Aoi, existed?
We couldn't find any.
It's possible that the facility's computers
and the staff's memories were tampered with...
But since we only have Togusa's word to go
on, there's no way to get a definitive answer.
What about the picture that girl was drawing?
We couldn't find that either.
Is that why he's going to turn in a
picture of a boy instead of a report?
Yeah, a handsome boy in a wheelchair
with a southpaw catcher's glove.
He's going to draw that using the
memories left in his cyberbrain.
A southpaw catcher's glove?
In internet slang that means,
"Although it seems it might exist, it doesn't".
I don't know about that.
Sorry for being late, Major.
Hey, I'll check it out if it's something
that can make up for your failure.
Prepare to be amazed, it's a masterpiece.
What the heck is this?
Looks like you got a weird memory
inserted from some weird place.
She's so cold and human
It's something humans do
She stays so cold in her soul, she's so number 9
She's incredible math
Just incredible math
And is she really human?
She says there's something new
But wake a lithium flower, just about to bloom
I smell lithium now
Smelling lithium now
How... is she what she doesn't say
She doesn't say
How is she when she doesn't suffer
I wonder what she does when she wakes up
When she wakes up